Email: jakubjehlik@fastmail.com

Jakub Jehlik

GitHub Profile
LinkedIn Profile

Software Engineer / Solution Architect
Prague, Czech Republic

Professional Summary

I'm an experienced IT professional interested in technology, software development, and the latest progress in the industry. I enjoy deep dives into complex problems and tackling them from all aspects to provide business value for the customer.

10 years of experience in the IT industry.

Experience in domain architecture, analysis, and design Sectors: automotive, finance, and utility

Agile / Scrum/waterfall / hybrid delivery

Experienced in International Delivery of large projects

Strong cultural awareness & communication skills

CSS/JS/React/Python (but also OOP languages C family)

Spoken Languages: English - fluent, German - passive, Czech - Native

Hobbies: Individual sports, guitar, dog training, software development, podcasts, mentoring

Experience

Deloitte - Solution Architect (Aug - Nov 2022, contract)

Outlining SDLC methodology for CE Region within the company. The project focused on the unifying approach to in-house development and customer engagement. Gathering existing artifacts and collaborating with many stakeholders on shaping the structure of a framework that will be used across the region.

- Prepared the SDLC document structure
- Outlined the general description and steps in each phase
- Shaped the document for approval by management
- Deloitte Consultant / Solution Analyst (Sep 2021 Apr 2022, contract)

Working on the new Skoda Portal - international project focused on delivering a world-wide central touchpoint for all Skoda customers.

- Review and analysis of technical/business aspects of the implementation
- UX/UI consultations in regards to the requirements
- Backlog preparation and prioritization
- Product owner and dev lead deputy

Trask - IT Solutions Architect (Sep 2020 - Oct 2021, contract)

Working on projects in automotive, finance and energy sectors focused on analysis, consulting, and architecture.

- Infrastructure and Architecture outline for process automation project in automotive
- DevOps process maturity evaluation
- Okta Identity management RFP and PoC
- Devops(Azure) CICD pipeline consultations
- Cloud(Azure/AWS) Infrastructure outline for new and existing projects

Actum - Solutions Architect (Mar 2019 - Jun 2020)

Working with large German manufacturer on e-commerce upgrade of their online presence including all kinds of integrations (data hub, CRM, media library, etc.) and their website. Communicating with all stakeholders on current development, planning, and execution. Preparing stories for developers and discussing technical and design aspects.

- Backlog preparation based on technical constraints and requirements.
- Verify REST API data availability for upcoming features
- UX/UI consultation with customers
- Overall solution architecture oversight

❖ Infor - Principal technical support Analyst (May 2013 - Dec 2018)

Working on industrial scale integration(SOA / middleware / ESB) among ERP software, Data Vaults, Reporting, and others. Troubleshooting information flow, system performance, scalability looking for better solutions in case of performance problems, etc.

Nowadays customers like Ferrari, Pfizer, and similar, require up-to-date information which can be shared across the company in real time to analyze sales, offer customizations, and deliver fast and better products. To get the most out of their data integration, either cloud-based only or hybrid(ST/MT/OnPrem) is introduced.

- Incident management, including prioritization and handling escalations
- Assisting and training new team members in Prague
- Liaising with Development and other internal departments to ensure proper handling of customer issues in line with agreed SLAs;
- Bug tracking and Defect Management (JIRA);
- Assisting in testing and verification of fixes/new customer deliverables by installation new versions and verifying compatibility with company's products and reporting any anomalies to Development;

- Working with customers for troubleshooting, testing, follow-up activities including remote desktop viewing.
- Creating test environments on Virtual Machines and installing relevant software versions, analyzing scripts and logs, and retrieving session/object information from the customer's environment;

Education

2004 – 2008 Gymnasium Dr. Vaclava Smejkala, Usti nad Labem, Stavbaru 5
☐ Completed with leaving examination, Czech Republic
2009-2010 Studies at the Faculty of the Czech Technical University in Prague field: Cybernetics;
not finished.